<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-24T12:58:50-04:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Dictionary of African Christian Biography</title><subtitle>To collect, preserve, and make freely accessible biographical accounts and church histories – from oral and written sources – integral to a scholarly understanding of African Christianity.</subtitle><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Church History Writing Workshop, Kinshasa, DRC, March 2023</title><link href="/church-history-workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Church History Writing Workshop, Kinshasa, DRC, March 2023" /><published>2023-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/church-history-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="/church-history-workshop/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/news/drc2023-workshop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Church History Workshop 2023&quot; class=&quot;bio&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Church History Writing Workshop for Congolese Mennonites March 20-24, 2023 - Centre Universitaire de Missiologie, Kinshasa, DR Congo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A personal report by Charly Ntumba Malembe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initiated by Anicka Fast, Doctor of Theology, the Workshop on Writing Church History for Congolese Mennonites, held from March 20 to 24, 2023 at the Centre Universitaire Missiologique in Kinshasa, is the very first initiative of its kind in the Democratic Republic of Congo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The selection of the sixteen participants (including two assistants) was based on a points system whereby the best candidates—from a total of 40 applications—were chosen. For my part, when I received the registration forms, I hesitated to apply. But an inner voice kept reminding me every day: “Go ahead, Charly, who knows? Maybe you will be selected. I was among the last, maybe even the very last one, to apply. The day Dr. Anicka contacted me to tell me the good news, I cried tears of joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this workshop was to develop the talents of Congolese writers and historians by equipping them with the necessary tools to write the biographies of the Mennonites (men and women) who contributed to the emergence of the Mennonite Church in the DR Congo. Produced by two eminent teachers, Dr. Anicka Fast (worker with Mennonite Mission Network) and Dr. Michèle Sigg (executive director of the Dictionary of African Christian Biography or DACB, www.DACB.org), in collaboration with Maurice Matsitsa of the Lay Protestant Ministry (MILAPRO) of the CEFMC, the workshop received financial and logistical support from several organizations including the Schowalter Foundation, the CUM, Mama Makeka House of Hope (MMHH), the Mennonite Central Committee (MCC) and Africa Inter-Mennonite Mission (AIMM). The result was a collaboration between Congolese Mennonite churches (CMCo, CEFMC, and CEM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop began with an opening worship service led by Reverend Matwala. The speaker, the Rev. Mupepe, provincial representative of the 4th CEFMC, city of Kinshasa, delivered the opening remarks and praised the initiative. He was preceded by the Rev. Vunda Michel, provincial representative of the CMCO. Mr. Maurice Matsitsa, coordinator and one of the participants, introduced the church officials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin the program, Dr. Michèle told us the story of Lydie Mengwelune (1886-1966, Cameroon)—a powerful testimony in the DACB that inspired us to pay attention to the other pioneers in our manual. Her presentation on the ancient and medieval church in Africa shed light on a little-known chapter in our history. It was the very first time that we learned that there were also black pioneers, both men and women, in the establishment of Christianity in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for Dr. Anicka Fast, the story of the Mennonite Church attracted a lot of attention from the participants, the majority of whom still knew that the first mission began in Djoko-Punda. Through her teaching, we learned the smallest details of the Mennonite mission. We are now able to even give lectures in our communities on the history of the church.
The workshop presented several highlights. First, the fact of bringing together members of the three Mennonite communities among which there was a diversity of languages (ethnic groups), ages, and provinces of origin (Kasai, Kasai Oriental, Sud-Kivu, Kwilu, Kinshasa) really proved to us that we are one body in Christ Jesus. The love and unity of the group was tremendous. Comedian Papa Mihala made us burst out laughing at all times, especially during our practical work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the candidacy of women was very much encouraged by the organizers. We saw how much this project showed consideration towards women: there were two women professors, a female village chief , five women out of sixteen participants, and the cooking was coordinated by women. This is the very first time that a woman was a village chief in a workshop with men and women where there were church leaders in the group. It was a very good memory for me, as village chief, to be the leader of our authorities! The women felt very valued in this workshop and cast off the inferiority complex that gnaws at us daily. Inspired by this first experience, women feel capable of assuming any responsibility in our Mennonite communities in particular and society in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning worship was another fantastic moment. The spirit of the Lord was present during our workshop and in the wonderful songs of each day. Sometimes I interrupted my teachers to wake up tired participants. God was present during our training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the different lessons taught by our two teachers encouraged us to always remain Mennonite Christians in the service of the Lord Jesus Christ. Our church leaders greatly appreciated the initiative and would like to see this workshop project on the writing of the history of the church continue. We, students, have mastered the scientific standards of this training and we are already at work in the field. We look forward to seeing our work published by the DACB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May God bless the work of our hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Launch of the Founding Chapter of the Friends of DACB</title><link href="/friends-of-dacb/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Launch of the Founding Chapter of the Friends of DACB" /><published>2022-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/friends-of-dacb</id><content type="html" xml:base="/friends-of-dacb/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;nimi-wariboko&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/news/nimi-dacbdinner.jpg&quot; class=&quot;bio&quot; /&gt;
On Wednesday, September 28, 2022 a small group of friends from the former Overseas Ministries Study Center (OMSC) and St. John’s Episcopal Church gathered at Oden House, in New Haven (CT) to celebrate the launch of the Founding Chapter of the Friends of DACB. Dr. Nimi Wariboko (&lt;a href=&quot;https://dacb.org/about/editorial-committee/&quot;&gt;DACB Executive Committee chair&lt;/a&gt;), Dr. Dana Robert (CGCM Director, DACB Executive Committee), Dr. Kyama Mugambi (Assistant Professor Yale Divinity School) and Dr. Michael Glerup (Director, Center for Early African Christianity) were among the attendees. Over a delicious meal cooked by Judy Stebbins who was aided by Chee Seng and Sharon Yip (former OMSC staff), guests heard two short presentations. In the first, Dr. Wariboko gave an &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/FR9puFbqNgs&quot;&gt;introduction to the DACB’s mission&lt;/a&gt;, and in the second, Executive Director Dr. Michele Sigg gave an &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/zbPoqpdJeI8&quot;&gt;overview&lt;/a&gt; of recent and ongoing initiatives entitled “In pursuit of conversion, connection, and restoration: The Dictionary of African Christian Biography, 2012 to 2022.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Sigg announced the appointment of Mrs. Judy Stebbins as chair of the Friends of DACB. The creation of the Friends of DACB was Mrs. Stebbins’ idea and generous initiative, as well as a mark of her deep friendship for DACB Founding Director Emeritus Jonathan Bonk (CGCM Faculty Associate) and Dr. Sigg. Mrs. Stebbins worked for many years in fundraising and development at Yale before becoming director of finance and housing at OMSC (2003-2019). From 2002 to 2015, she raised a million dollars in reserve funds for the Community Dining Room in Branford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Friends of DACB is a community of individuals invested in the work of world Christianity/mission, global networks, scholarship, theological education, and shalom in the church in Africa. The particular focus of the Friends of DACB is to support the work of the Dictionary of African Christian Biography Project by assisting with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Promotion: Publicizing the mission of the DACB, and recruiting writers, instructors, and institutions in view of gathering more content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Financial sustainability: Providing a core amount of money to sustain the project and help it to grow into the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Networking: Helping to find collaborators in academia, web development, publishing houses, church leadership, mission agencies, educational institutions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prayer for the DACB / JACB and all those working for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the hope of all involved that this founding chapter will be one of several groups of “Friends of DACB” across the continent. &lt;br /&gt;
We invite you to join!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For more information or to join, contact:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mrs. Judy Stebbins (Chair, Friends of DACB), email jcistebbins@gmail.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Or Dr. Michele Sigg (Executive Director, DACB), email: dacb@bu.edu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">On Wednesday, September 28, 2022 a small group of friends from the former Overseas Ministries Study Center (OMSC) and St. John’s Episcopal Church gathered at Oden House, in New Haven (CT) to celebrate the launch of the Founding Chapter of the Friends of DACB. Dr. Nimi Wariboko (DACB Executive Committee chair), Dr. Dana Robert (CGCM Director, DACB Executive Committee), Dr. Kyama Mugambi (Assistant Professor Yale Divinity School) and Dr. Michael Glerup (Director, Center for Early African Christianity) were among the attendees. Over a delicious meal cooked by Judy Stebbins who was aided by Chee Seng and Sharon Yip (former OMSC staff), guests heard two short presentations. In the first, Dr. Wariboko gave an introduction to the DACB’s mission, and in the second, Executive Director Dr. Michele Sigg gave an overview of recent and ongoing initiatives entitled “In pursuit of conversion, connection, and restoration: The Dictionary of African Christian Biography, 2012 to 2022.”</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Jonathan Bonk Steps Down as Director of the DACB</title><link href="/director-retires/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jonathan Bonk Steps Down as Director of the DACB" /><published>2020-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/director-retires</id><content type="html" xml:base="/director-retires/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;jonathan-bonk&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/editorial-committee/bonk-jon.jpg&quot; class=&quot;bio&quot; /&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;../dacb.org/resources/journal/5-4/5-4-OCT2020-JACB-ejournal.pdf&quot;&gt;October 2020 issue&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Journal of African Christian Biography&lt;/em&gt; (JACB) is dedicated to JACB and DACB Founder Professor Jonathan Bonk on the occasion of his retirement. Both these publications (JACB and DACB) are unique, specializing in the collection and preservation of biographies of African Christians—accompanied by scholarly reflection—from the full spectrum of Christianity across the continent of Africa. Contributors are Christian scholars familiar with the dioceses, parishes, and congregations of the people featured. The collection also includes manuscripts authored by the people featured as well as photographs and other digital resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Bonk, born of Canadian Mennonite missionaries and brought up in Ethiopia, is currently Research Professor of Mission Studies at Boston University, Massachusetts. He is the author of &lt;em&gt;Missions and Money: Affluence as a Missionary Problem&lt;/em&gt;, which remains one of the most challenging books in this field of research.  He also served as Executive Director of the Overseas Ministries Study Center (OMSC) in New Haven, Connecticut where he mentored visiting scholars in addition to his role as administrator and editor of the International Bulletin of Missionary Research (IBMR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My acquaintance with Professor Bonk dates from his first exploratory visit to Nairobi in 1999 when he introduced us to the DACB Project. Since then we have learned much from him – and continue to learn – even during his retirement. He is an exemplary mentor and a visionary leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professor Jesse Mugambi&lt;/strong&gt;, from the Introduction to the October 2020 Journal issue&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The October 2020 issue of the Journal of African Christian Biography (JACB) is dedicated to JACB and DACB Founder Professor Jonathan Bonk on the occasion of his retirement. Both these publications (JACB and DACB) are unique, specializing in the collection and preservation of biographies of African Christians—accompanied by scholarly reflection—from the full spectrum of Christianity across the continent of Africa. Contributors are Christian scholars familiar with the dioceses, parishes, and congregations of the people featured. The collection also includes manuscripts authored by the people featured as well as photographs and other digital resources.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">News Release: Members Added to the Executive Committee</title><link href="/new-editorial-members/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="News Release: Members Added to the Executive Committee" /><published>2019-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/new-editorial-members</id><content type="html" xml:base="/new-editorial-members/">&lt;p&gt;We lament the departure from this life on January 6 of our beloved Professor Lamin Sanneh. In addition to being a close personal friend, he was a staunch supporter and advocate of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.DACB.org&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dictionary of African Christian Biography&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Since 1995, when the DACB began to show signs of becoming more than just an idea, he steadily supported the venture by word and by deed, as a consultant, supporter, advisory council member, and as a member of the Executive Committee. He will be sorely missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are therefore pleased to announce two new members who will be joining the Executive Committee effective immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/editorial-committee/jmugambi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mugambi&quot; class=&quot;bio&quot; /&gt;
Professor Dr. Jesse N. K. Mugambi (PhD, FKNAS, EBS), from Kenya, has been an active and effective member of the Africa Advisory Council since 2014. He is Professor of Philosophy and Religious Studies, University of Nairobi, from which he graduated with his BA, MA and PhD.  Prof. Mugambi is a committed churchman (Anglican), an exemplary ecumenist and networker, and an extraordinarily productive academic whose interests, ranging across disciplinary lines, have resulted in many noteworthy publications, among which are: &lt;em&gt;Christianity and the African Cultural Heritage&lt;/em&gt; (2005); “Climate Change and Food Security: A Challenge for African Christianity” and “Profile of African Christianity at Home and in the West” in &lt;em&gt;Anthology of African Christianity&lt;/em&gt; (Regnum 2017); &lt;em&gt;African Theology of Reconstruction&lt;/em&gt; (Butare 2016);  “The Future of Theological Education in Africa and the Challenges it Faces” and  “Challenges for Theological Publishing of Scholarly books in Africa” in &lt;em&gt;Handbook of Theological Education in Africa&lt;/em&gt; (Regnum; 2013); &lt;em&gt;Christianity and African Culture&lt;/em&gt; (Acton 1989, 2000, 2002); &lt;em&gt;Contextual Theology Across Cultures&lt;/em&gt; (Acton 2009, with Michael R. Guy). His global travels, extensive consulting, and established contacts with colleagues in institutions across Africa, the Americas, Asia and Europe have proven greatly beneficial to the DACB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/editorial-committee/wariboko-nimi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wariboko&quot; class=&quot;bio&quot; /&gt;
Professor Dr. Nimi Wariboko is the Walter G. Muelder Professor of Social Ethics at Boston University School of Theology. He holds a PhD in Ethics (Suma Cum Laude) from Princeton Theological Seminary, an MBA in Finance and Accounting from Columbia University in New York City, and a B.Sc. (Economics, first class honors) from University of Port Harcourt, Nigeria. An extraordinarily creative and productive academic, both the originality and range of Dr. Nimi Wariboko’s scholarship is attested by his numerous publications in the fields of economic ethics, Christian social ethics, African social traditions, Pentecostal studies, and philosophical theology. Five of his many books are representative of his scholarly energy, originality, and range: &lt;em&gt;The Principle of Excellence: A Framework for Social Ethics&lt;/em&gt; (Lexington 2009);  &lt;em&gt;God and Money: A Theology of Money in a Globalizing World&lt;/em&gt; (Lexington 1955);  &lt;em&gt;Ethics and Time: Ethos of Temporal Orientation in Politics and Religion of the Niger Delta&lt;/em&gt; (Lexington 2010);  &lt;em&gt;The Pentecostal Principle: Ethical Methodology in New Spirit&lt;/em&gt; (Eerdmans 2012); and  &lt;em&gt;Economics in Spirit and Truth: A Moral Philosophy of Finance&lt;/em&gt; (Palgrave Macmillan 2014). He has followed with interest the development of the DACB, and looks forward to working with us to ensure the ongoing viability, credibility, functionality, and dissemination of the resource.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We lament the departure from this life on January 6 of our beloved Professor Lamin Sanneh. In addition to being a close personal friend, he was a staunch supporter and advocate of the Dictionary of African Christian Biography. Since 1995, when the DACB began to show signs of becoming more than just an idea, he steadily supported the venture by word and by deed, as a consultant, supporter, advisory council member, and as a member of the Executive Committee. He will be sorely missed.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">DACB to Collaborate with Jesuit Historical Institute In Africa</title><link href="/JHIA-newpartner/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DACB to Collaborate with Jesuit Historical Institute In Africa" /><published>2019-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/JHIA-newpartner</id><content type="html" xml:base="/JHIA-newpartner/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/news/jhia-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;JHIA logo&quot; class=&quot;bio&quot; /&gt;
The Jesuit Historical Institute in Africa (JHIA), located in Nairobi, Kenya, is an institute dedicated to preserving memory and promoting knowledge in Africa and its adjacent islands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JHIA started in 2010 as an idea of the Jesuit General, Adolfo Nicholás, S.J., to encourage the study of his Order’s largely unexplored involvement in the evangelization of Africa. Further deliberations pointed to the need for such a study to be carried out within a broader social, political, cultural and religious context. The JHIA’s vision was thus expanded to that of offering a cost-effective environment for ground-breaking research on the religious histories, cultures and traditions of the people of Africa and Madagascar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jhia.ac.ke/&quot;&gt;JHIA website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jhia.ac.ke/component/content/article/85-who-we-are/130-institutional-partners&quot;&gt;JHIA institutional partners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Jesuit Historical Institute in Africa (JHIA), located in Nairobi, Kenya, is an institute dedicated to preserving memory and promoting knowledge in Africa and its adjacent islands.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">An African Giant Has Died: Lamin Sanneh</title><link href="/death-of-a-giant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An African Giant Has Died: Lamin Sanneh" /><published>2019-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/death-of-a-giant</id><content type="html" xml:base="/death-of-a-giant/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/news/lamin-andrew2013.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lamin and Andrew&quot; class=&quot;bio&quot; /&gt;
It is with great sadness that we announce the death of Professor Lamin Sanneh on January 6, 2019.&lt;br /&gt;
Sanneh served on the charter Advisory Council of the DACB that began in 1995 and, in recent years, he was a member of the Editorial Committee. When I received the news of his death Monday morning, I was overwhelmed with a terrible feeling of loss. The article I was editing was full of references to his work. His name appears on many pages of the DACB website. The sight of his name on the spines of the books surrounding me suddenly brought a sense of grief that remains with me. I will always remember his guidance, wisdom, and encouragement in my work for the DACB. The community of scholars in Africa and the West will feel the loss of his light for years to come. &lt;br /&gt;
Below are a few tributes in his memory from DACB Editors and Advisors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michele Sigg, DACB Associate Director and JACB Managing Editor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo: Lamin Sanneh and Andrew Walls, charter Advisory Council members (date of the photo: 2003)
Credit: Rev. Dan Nicholas&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jonathan Bonk, director of the &lt;em&gt;Dictionary of African Christian Biography&lt;/em&gt;, Center for Global Christianity and Mission at Boston University&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first met Lamin in 1979 at the University of Aberdeen, where I was studying under Andrew Walls. Lamin, recently graduated from the School of African and Oriental Studies (SOAS) at London University with a PhD in Islamic History, had been recruited by Walls to fill a gap in the Department of Religious Studies. To Lamin’s surprise, a year after arriving he was “invited” to teach the required seminar on Christianity as a World Religion. He was too polite to decline … and the rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was gripped by the phenomenon of contemporary Christianity as a primarily non-Western religion. He became one of the best informed and most trusted interpreters of world Christianity and Islam of his generation. As comfortable with some of Islam’s most gifted intellectuals as he was with Christians in the upper echelons of ecclesiology and academia, his deeply informed understanding of and appreciate for both faiths combined with his modesty and his eloquence to make him a unique and much sought after voice in an era more characterized by reductionist polarizations than by deep understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A committed Christian, Lamin understood and appreciated his Muslim roots. His last major book—&lt;em&gt;Beyond Jihad: The Pacifist Tradition in West African Islam&lt;/em&gt; (OUP 2016)—had, he told me over Turkish lunch, left him intellectually and physically exhausted. It was, he thought, his magnum opus, and he doubted that he would attempt another one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Physically, he was an imposing figure; intellectually, he was even more impressive. These qualities were combined with deep personal modesty and a willingness to listen carefully to what others had to say. One of my favorite experiences for many years was his summation at the end of each annual Yale-Edinburgh Group on the History of Missionary Movement and World Christianity meeting, now anticipating its 29th year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lamin was fond of pointing out that those who gathered were simply a group of friends from around the world who shared a common academic interest and who gathered alternative years at the University of Edinburgh and Yale University to read papers, discuss issues, share points-of-view, and encourage each other. At the end of these two and a half day marathons–in which Lamin inevitably sat in the front row deep in thought, with his eyes closed–he would provide an eloquent verbatim summary of the event, respectfully referencing every presentation and its author, knitting the disparate pieces together into a picture that was better than we knew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now my good friend is home at last—summoned from the margins to the Center. He is sorely missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.christianitytoday.com/news/2019/january/lamin-sanneh-died-world-christianity-islam-africa-yale.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christianity Today International&lt;/em&gt;, January 8, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dana L. Robert, director of the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at Boston University School of Theology; Editorial Committee, &lt;em&gt;Dictionary of African Christian Biography&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Lamin Sanneh was a giant in the field of World Christianity. His loss sends a tidal wave across multiple fields, institutions, and continents. He will be sorely missed by those of us who worked with him and called him friend, as well as by people who knew him only from his powerful writings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an African, a superb scholar, and a convert from Islam, Lamin Sanneh saw from the outside what those raised on the inside could not. His 1989 book &lt;em&gt;Translating the Message&lt;/em&gt; showed how the gospel could become part of every culture, through being translated into the language and worldview of the people. He challenged the assumption that Christianity was merely a tool of western colonizers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through his founding of the annual Yale-Edinburgh conferences on mission history, his publications, his editorship of the Oxford University Press World Christianity Series, his leadership of the &lt;em&gt;Dictionary of African Christian Biography&lt;/em&gt;, and many other important projects, Lamin Sanneh collaborated with others to transform the study of mission history, African religions, and World Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.christianitytoday.com/news/2019/january/lamin-sanneh-died-world-christianity-islam-africa-yale.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christianity Today International&lt;/em&gt;, January 8, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Philomena Njeri Mwaura, Director, Centre for Gender Equity and Empowerment; Associate Professor, Department of Philosophy and Religious Studies, Kenyatta University; DACB Advisory Council member&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a tragedy!  I have received the news of the passing of Prof Sanneh with great shock and sadness! I have no words to say to his family, colleagues and friends. His passing is a great loss to the African academic fraternity and globally. I had the privilege to meet him severally in New Haven and at the conference on African Christian Biography sometimes back in Boston. He will always be remembered because of his ground breaking work on African Christianity. May the Lord comfort his family and give them the strength to bear this great loss. Fare thee well Prof. Sanneh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Source: email dated January 8, 2019)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jesse Mugambi,  Ecumenist; World Council of Churches; Professor of Philosophy and Religious Studies, University of Nairobi, Kenya; DACB Advisory Council member&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lamin Sanneh [was] one of the most admirable role-models for African Academia—-both within our continent and among the African diaspora in Europe and North America. His death has come only a few months after that of Professor James H. Cone on 28th April 2018. As we mourn these great scholars, the greatest and most worthwhile tributes with which to honor them, will be our own endeavor to emulate them— each of us in our respective specializations and vocations, especially the published works of Lamin Sanneh and James H. Cone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Source: email dated January 7, 2019)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Esther E. Acolatse, associate professor of pastoral theology and intercultural studies at Knox College at the University of Toronto; DACB Advisory Council member&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m overwhelmed with sadness even as I recall fond memories of Professor Lamin Sanneh … This past year has been enriched by his astute mind and generosity to a younger colleague. I was pleasantly surprised by his thoughtful engagement of my work in a foreword to my latest book and an extended conversation with him in April as well as November where it was clear he still had a lot to contribute to the shaping of the field of global Christianity and its tenor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shared a couple of devotions he had authored for &lt;em&gt;The Christian Century&lt;/em&gt; in 1989 and suggested that we could write and make such devotions available to the African Church and beyond. Those devotions coupled with his vast academic writing brought me face to face with the mind and spiritual life behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I asked how he found time to write so much. He simply said: “Because I’m afraid one day I’ll be asked by God to give account of how I have used my time. I want to be able to bear up under that question.”” Just less than a month ago, we communicated as he waited to board a plane from Accra, and his hopes for my involvement with the new center just named for him. Now, labor over, he joins the church triumphant. His works and the many lives he has touched will continue to bear testimony to a life faithfully lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.christianitytoday.com/news/2019/january/lamin-sanneh-died-world-christianity-islam-africa-yale.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christianity Today International&lt;/em&gt;, January 8, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other tributes by John Azumah, J. Kwabena Asamoah-Gyadu, Joel Carpenter, and Edith Blumhofer can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.christianitytoday.com/news/2019/january/lamin-sanneh-died-world-christianity-islam-africa-yale.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christianity Today International&lt;/em&gt;, January 8, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tributes collected from DACB readers and associates.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recognized pioneer in the exploding interdisciplinary field of World Christianity, Lamin was a rare scholar who combined rhetorical eloquence with scholarly erudition, and religious conviction with child-like curiosity. Arguing, for example, that the missionary movement’s greatest gift to the peoples of the world was Bible translation, he sought to free us from our presuppositions and hubris, saying, “It is not so much that the West transmitted the gospel to world but that the cultures of the world discovered the gospel when they heard the Bible in their mother tongues.” This profound insight from a convert from Islam into the intrinsic and infinite translatability of the gospel still has not been understood or heeded by much of the Western theological academy. (…) In the past thirty years, there is hardly a dissertation in the fields of Missiology, World Christianity, Missional Theology, or Intercultural Theology that fails to reference Sanneh’s work.&lt;br /&gt;
  -From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.omsc.org/news/2019/1/18/in-memoriam&quot;&gt;Overseas Ministries Study Center website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh no! What a loss to the global church and the global church community. Three years ago, I spent the most beautiful time with Prof Sanneh at a workshop organised by Calvin College’s the Nagel Institute in Kenya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once every 50 years a theologian comes along whose contribution is so profound that the course of a discipline is changed. Sanneh was one such a scholar. Few scholars have highlighted African agency and Africa’s contribution to world Christianity as incisively and insightfully as Lamin Sanneh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tinyiko Maluleke&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/8/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May his soul rest in peace and rise in glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;africanchurch@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a sad news!
The death of an exceptional person leaves a terrible void but also a considerable moral legacy. We are carriers of this flame that Prof. Lamin Sanneh lit in our hearts … We are custodians of his memory. We will never forget him and he will live forever.
May the Lord comfort his family, institutions, and friends.
May his soul rest in peace.
Best Regards,
Priscille&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rev. Prof. Priscille Djomhoué&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professeur de Nouveau Testament
Faculté Universitaire de Théologie Protestante
Rue des Bollandistes 40, B-1040 Bruxelles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Lord have mercy. I just made reference to him this afternoon. Very shocked at the news. May his soul rest in peace. My deepest condolences to his family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Korku Laryea&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is with deep sadness that Prof. Lamin Sanneh has transited prematurelly. His Sterling contribution in the development and growth of the Dictionary of African Biography will remain as a monument in the llife and work of DACB. My sincere condolences to DACB and to his family.
Silas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very Rev. Prof. Silas Ncozana
Chuluchosema Pastor
P.O. Box 5115 Limbe
Tel. No. 0888377732
Malawi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To: The Family and Friends of Late Prof. Lamin Sanneh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re: TRIBUTE TO LATE PROFESSOR LAMIN SANNEH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news of the demise of Prof. Lamin Sanneh came to me as a rude shock. We are missing a member of the intelligesia, Prof. Lamin Sanneh was a legend and a humble researcher full of love, strength and encouragement. We shall never forget your contributions to the theological community. May your gentle soul rest in perfect peace, and may God grant us all the fortitude to bear this great loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His Holiness, The Most Revd. Dr. Rufus Okikiola OSITELU (PhD Computer Science; PhD Religious Studies);  Aladura Patriarch &amp;amp; Primate of The Church of the Lord (Prayer Fellowship) Worldwide [TCLPFW] a.k.a TCLAW;  P. O. Box 71, Shagamu;10/12 Primate Ositelu Street;  Ogere-Remo; Ogun State, Nigeria, West Africa; Tel.: +234-803-7263902;      +234-803-0850226;       +234-816-588-5990; cla.primate@gmail.com;  cla_primate@yahoo.com;  cla_primate@hotmail.com;  www.aladura.net   /   www.tclpfw.org   /   www.tclaw.org  /  www.the-church-of-the-lord-aladura-worldwide.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Demise of Prof. Lamin Sanneh:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a sad news to begin the new year with!
With the demise of Prof. Sanneh, Africa has  lost one of his most committed scholars and theologians of interreligious and intercultural dialogue. In all his writings, lectures and inter-personal and communal encounters, Prof. Sanneh always brought with him his  magnanimous spirit. This is most apparent in all his works and writings from an African perspective  on the North-South dialogue. You just need to take up and read his ,”Whose Religion is Christianity”, or his magnus opus, “Translating the Message”, and above all his master-piece author-biography, “Summoned from the Margin: Homecoming of An African.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prof. Sanneh has been a great source of inspiration and model to many young African theologians. My consolation here is that through my suggestion, some of my students had written their dissertations, even up to doctorate on the thoughts of Lamin Sanneh, especially on the subjects of intercultural encounters and translating the message. Furthermore, the life experience, his religious and conversion journey of Prof. Sanneh, from Islam to Christianity, and from one Christian denomination to another singled him out as a unique figure and man of faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My condolences to his wife and children, and also to his academic family at the Yale University, and numerous students, friends and acquaintances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the demise of Lamin Sanneh, Africa has lost one of his greatest scholars and theologians of the 20th and 21st centuries. May God receive his good soul and strengthen his family he has left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Text of tribute by Fr. Oborji, &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/bio-pdfs/gambia/sanneh-lamin1.pdf&quot;&gt;“Lamin Sanneh: A Foremost African Theologian from the Gambia”–PDF file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fr. Francis Anekwe Oborji
(Professor Ordinarius of contextual theology, Pontifical Urbaniana University, Rome)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is indeed sad news to hear. We have indeed lost an academic giant. I was fortunate to get one of his famous books “Translating the Message,” through your inspiration. I will keep him in my prayers as well as his family and well-wishers he left behind. Thank you for this information as usual. May God continue to bless you with more wisdom and good health. Have a wonderful new year!
Fr. Fred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FR. CHIMA FREDRICK MBIERE, BA, PH.D.
Resurrection Parish
410 Anne Street
PO Box 47 Illiopolis,
IL 62539-0047, USA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is sad to learn of the death of Prof.Sanneh. His contributions to this monumental task of DACB will  live to pay him greater tribute. May the good Lord reward him with eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul Nchoji Nkwi, DACB Advisory Council&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sorry for the loss of Lamim Sanneh. May God receive him in His glory and support his family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bishop Pierre-Claver Ngezahayo
Eglise Wesleyenne du Burundi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/10/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pray for you all to be comforted of the Lord in this loss.
May his soul rest in peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Regards,
From Africa Brotherhood Church&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/10/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for sending me this sad news.  I remember several presentations made of the significance of Christ to Muslims.
His death is a great loss to us.
I hope I will be back from church in time to hear part of his funeral service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely,
Russell Staples&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/10/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Prof. O.,
I just finished reading your mail announcing to me the demise of an African academic giant, Prof. Lamin Sanneh.  Thanks for the information. It’s really sad that we (Africa)  and indeed the world has lost such a special gift to humanity.
I thank you immensely for directing me to the world of the thoughts of Prof.  Lamin Sanneh for both my Licentiate and Doctorate. His works are naturally revolutionary and compelling in character. His boldness and clarity of thought are disarming and endearing.
May God grant him eternal rest and console his immediate family in particular and his academic family in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ferdinand Ndubuisi Okoli
Christ the King Parish Amata Mgbowo,  Enugu, Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/11/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tribute to Professor Lamin Sanneh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first introduction to Professor Lamin Sanneh was at New College, Edinburgh in 1991.  Professor Andrew Walls had invited Lamin Sanneh for a series of lectures geared towards a small group of us involved in the Study of Christianity in the Non-Western World.  Lamin skillfully opened blinders that limited my vision of God’s Great Kingdom in the world.  And then in 2006, during Lila’s and my six month stint at OMSC, we had occasion to fraternise with Lamin a number of times.  What impressed me about this “giant of a scholar” was his humility, his probing questions, his boisterous laughter, and his disarming manner of pricking the balloons of western missionaries who had a penchant for taking ourselves too seriously.  Lamin Sanneh, together with Andrew Walls, played a significant role in steering my doctoral research towards the history and rich narratives of hundreds of indigenous evangelists who valiantly proclaimed the Jesus story in southern Ethiopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E. Paul Balisky (PhD)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/12/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow me to give my heart felt condolences.
Human days are like a burning candle, at one moment in time the candle will burn out. It was with great sadness that news of the demise of the son of Africa reached us.
Surely like writing in the sand our lives are just as brief memory which fades with time.
From my understanding, death is not the end. I thank God for the many writings Lamin has inspired many, we give tribute for the work and life despite the challenges of life , with all its turns and twist I thank God that This great Son of Africa has influenced and touched us.
The demise indeed  is a great loss especially to his family and wiring fraternity.
For those who knew Lamin personally, forever in your hearts fond memories with great love will never be erased.
RIP
Yours, Kabīrū Fredrick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/14/2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was saddened to hear about the sudden death of Professor Lamin Sanneh a very distinguished son of Africa. We shall all miss him but we thank God for the phenomenal contribution he made to the history of Christianity in Africa and beyond and we pray that his should should rest in peace and that God should grant him a crown of glory. Our prayers go to his family and relatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James Amanze, DACB Advisory Council&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/14/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The late Prof Sanneh, will be dearly missed.  He has however left an important legacy for us all.  My wish is that his family and all his loved ones will find God’s grace sufficient to carry them/us during this taxing moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madipoane Masenya, DACB Advisory Council&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/15/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thank God for the life and service of Laminah Sanneh. May God encourage and comfort his family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edison Kalengyo, DACB Advisory Council&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Source: email dated 1/15/2019)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It is with great sadness that we announce the death of Professor Lamin Sanneh on January 6, 2019. Sanneh served on the charter Advisory Council of the DACB that began in 1995 and, in recent years, he was a member of the Editorial Committee. When I received the news of his death Monday morning, I was overwhelmed with a terrible feeling of loss. The article I was editing was full of references to his work. His name appears on many pages of the DACB website. The sight of his name on the spines of the books surrounding me suddenly brought a sense of grief that remains with me. I will always remember his guidance, wisdom, and encouragement in my work for the DACB. The community of scholars in Africa and the West will feel the loss of his light for years to come. Below are a few tributes in his memory from DACB Editors and Advisors.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Release of African Christian Biography Volume</title><link href="/ACB-VOLUME/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release of African Christian Biography Volume" /><published>2018-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/ACB-VOLUME</id><content type="html" xml:base="/ACB-VOLUME/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/news/acbvolume2018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ACB Volume&quot; class=&quot;bio&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Cluster Publications&lt;/strong&gt; of South Africa has just released &lt;em&gt;African Christian Biography&lt;/em&gt;, edited by Dana L. Robert, a volume of the proceedings of the African Christian Biography Conference held at Boston University in October 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About this book&lt;/strong&gt;:
The papers in this volume narrate the histories of leading African Christians, and reflect on the meaning of writing African Christian biographies. Written to celebrate the &lt;em&gt;Dictionary of African Christian Biography&lt;/em&gt; (www.dacb.org), this volume shows why remembering the lives of Christian leaders remains important for understanding African history, Christian identities, and African contributions to the shaping of World Christianity. The authors include some of the world’s leading scholars of African Christianity in its social, political, and theological contexts. Subjects of the papers range from an Ethiopian saint, to kings and queens, history making Protestant pastors, and women whose hidden stories undergird their transformative
leadership of family, church and society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may view or download:
 &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/ACB-volume-index.pdf&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/ACB-volume-flier.pdf&quot;&gt;Promotional flier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Cluster Publications of South Africa has just released African Christian Biography, edited by Dana L. Robert, a volume of the proceedings of the African Christian Biography Conference held at Boston University in October 2015.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">DACB Advisory Council Meeting: October 6-9, 2017</title><link href="/DACB-advisory-meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DACB Advisory Council Meeting: October 6-9, 2017" /><published>2017-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/DACB-advisory-meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DACB-advisory-meeting/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/news/orth-church2017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trinity Orthodox Church&quot; class=&quot;bio&quot; /&gt;The DACB Advisory Council meeting was held October 6-9, 2017 in Nairobi, Kenya at the St. Mary Magdalene Retreat Center, located at Resurrection Gardens. This year, we had the joy of welcoming from Cameroon Professor Paul Nkwi who had not been able to join us in previous years due to visa problems. The group attended Sunday worship service at Trinity Orthodox Church. One focus of the discussions was the promotion and distribution of the &lt;em&gt;Journal of African Christian Biography&lt;/em&gt; in African institutions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The DACB Advisory Council meeting was held October 6-9, 2017 in Nairobi, Kenya at the St. Mary Magdalene Retreat Center, located at Resurrection Gardens. This year, we had the joy of welcoming from Cameroon Professor Paul Nkwi who had not been able to join us in previous years due to visa problems. The group attended Sunday worship service at Trinity Orthodox Church. One focus of the discussions was the promotion and distribution of the Journal of African Christian Biography in African institutions.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Complete Redesign of DACB Website</title><link href="/new-site/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Complete Redesign of DACB Website" /><published>2017-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/new-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="/new-site/">&lt;p&gt;This summer, the DACB website underwent a complete redesign using a flat-file CMS system conceived by leading software development platform Github. The new site has a lightweight digital footprint, loads fast, and can be distributed on USB drives in areas without Internet access. In addition, multiple indexes and a powerful standalone search engine (that works offline) make it easy to do in-depth research on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indexing of subjects (as catechists, martyrs, etc) is still underway and will hopefully be completed by November. Please do not hesitate to contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dacb@bu.edu&quot;&gt;dacb@bu.edu&lt;/a&gt; if you see anything that needs correcting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This summer, the DACB website underwent a complete redesign using a flat-file CMS system conceived by leading software development platform Github. The new site has a lightweight digital footprint, loads fast, and can be distributed on USB drives in areas without Internet access. In addition, multiple indexes and a powerful standalone search engine (that works offline) make it easy to do in-depth research on the site.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Resources for Research: Newly Redesigned Website for Old &amp;amp; New in Shona at Boston University</title><link href="/shona-new/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resources for Research: Newly Redesigned Website for Old &amp; New in Shona at Boston University" /><published>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/shona-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="/shona-new/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://sites.bu.edu/shonareligion/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; is the fruit of about 6 years of work by graduate students from the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at BU who scanned roughly 1,200 of Dr. Inus Daneel’s photographs of life among the AICs and Traditionalists from the 1960s on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a sample 4-minute audio slide narrated by Daneel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K5jqsi9qzsM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The website is the fruit of about 6 years of work by graduate students from the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at BU who scanned roughly 1,200 of Dr. Inus Daneel’s photographs of life among the AICs and Traditionalists from the 1960s on.</summary></entry></feed>