<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-08T15:05:28-04:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Dictionary of African Christian Biography</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">News Release: Members Added to the Executive Committee</title><link href="/new-editorial-members/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="News Release: Members Added to the Executive Committee" /><published>2019-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/new-editorial-members</id><content type="html" xml:base="/new-editorial-members/">We lament the departure from this life on January 6 of our beloved Professor Lamin Sanneh. In addition to being a close personal friend, he was a staunch supporter and advocate of the [*Dictionary of African Christian Biography*](https://www.DACB.org). Since 1995, when the DACB began to show signs of becoming more than just an idea, he steadily supported the venture by word and by deed, as a consultant, supporter, advisory council member, and as a member of the Executive Committee. He will be sorely missed.

We are therefore pleased to announce two new members who will be joining the Executive Committee effective immediately.  

***

![mugambi](/images/editorial-committee/jmugambi.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}
Professor Dr. Jesse N. K. Mugambi (PhD, FKNAS, EBS), from Kenya, has been an active and effective member of the Africa Advisory Council since 2014. He is Professor of Philosophy and Religious Studies, University of Nairobi, from which he graduated with his BA, MA and PhD.  Prof. Mugambi is a committed churchman (Anglican), an exemplary ecumenist and networker, and an extraordinarily productive academic whose interests, ranging across disciplinary lines, have resulted in many noteworthy publications, among which are: *Christianity and the African Cultural Heritage* (2005); “Climate Change and Food Security: A Challenge for African Christianity” and “Profile of African Christianity at Home and in the West” in *Anthology of African Christianity* (Regnum 2017); *African Theology of Reconstruction* (Butare 2016);  “The Future of Theological Education in Africa and the Challenges it Faces” and  &quot;Challenges for Theological Publishing of Scholarly books in Africa&quot; in *Handbook of Theological Education in Africa* (Regnum; 2013); *Christianity and African Culture* (Acton 1989, 2000, 2002); *Contextual Theology Across Cultures* (Acton 2009, with Michael R. Guy). His global travels, extensive consulting, and established contacts with colleagues in institutions across Africa, the Americas, Asia and Europe have proven greatly beneficial to the DACB.


![wariboko](/images/editorial-committee/wariboko-nimi.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}
Professor Dr. Nimi Wariboko is the Walter G. Muelder Professor of Social Ethics at Boston University School of Theology. He holds a PhD in Ethics (Suma Cum Laude) from Princeton Theological Seminary, an MBA in Finance and Accounting from Columbia University in New York City, and a B.Sc. (Economics, first class honors) from University of Port Harcourt, Nigeria. An extraordinarily creative and productive academic, both the originality and range of Dr. Nimi Wariboko’s scholarship is attested by his numerous publications in the fields of economic ethics, Christian social ethics, African social traditions, Pentecostal studies, and philosophical theology. Five of his many books are representative of his scholarly energy, originality, and range: *The Principle of Excellence: A Framework for Social Ethics* (Lexington 2009);  *God and Money: A Theology of Money in a Globalizing World* (Lexington 1955);  *Ethics and Time: Ethos of Temporal Orientation in Politics and Religion of the Niger Delta* (Lexington 2010);  *The Pentecostal Principle: Ethical Methodology in New Spirit* (Eerdmans 2012); and  *Economics in Spirit and Truth: A Moral Philosophy of Finance* (Palgrave Macmillan 2014). He has followed with interest the development of the DACB, and looks forward to working with us to ensure the ongoing viability, credibility, functionality, and dissemination of the resource.</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We lament the departure from this life on January 6 of our beloved Professor Lamin Sanneh. In addition to being a close personal friend, he was a staunch supporter and advocate of the Dictionary of African Christian Biography. Since 1995, when the DACB began to show signs of becoming more than just an idea, he steadily supported the venture by word and by deed, as a consultant, supporter, advisory council member, and as a member of the Executive Committee. He will be sorely missed.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">DACB to Collaborate with Jesuit Historical Institute In Africa</title><link href="/JHIA-newpartner/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DACB to Collaborate with Jesuit Historical Institute In Africa" /><published>2019-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/JHIA-newpartner</id><content type="html" xml:base="/JHIA-newpartner/">![JHIA logo](/images/news/jhia-logo.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}
The Jesuit Historical Institute in Africa (JHIA), located in Nairobi, Kenya, is an institute dedicated to preserving memory and promoting knowledge in Africa and its adjacent islands.  

JHIA started in 2010 as an idea of the Jesuit General, Adolfo Nicholás, S.J., to encourage the study of his Order's largely unexplored involvement in the evangelization of Africa. Further deliberations pointed to the need for such a study to be carried out within a broader social, political, cultural and religious context. The JHIA's vision was thus expanded to that of offering a cost-effective environment for ground-breaking research on the religious histories, cultures and traditions of the people of Africa and Madagascar.

Links:  
[JHIA website](https://www.jhia.ac.ke/)

[JHIA institutional partners](https://www.jhia.ac.ke/component/content/article/85-who-we-are/130-institutional-partners)</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Jesuit Historical Institute in Africa (JHIA), located in Nairobi, Kenya, is an institute dedicated to preserving memory and promoting knowledge in Africa and its adjacent islands.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">An African Giant Has Died: Lamin Sanneh</title><link href="/death-of-a-giant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An African Giant Has Died: Lamin Sanneh" /><published>2019-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/death-of-a-giant</id><content type="html" xml:base="/death-of-a-giant/">![Lamin and Andrew](/images/news/lamin-andrew2013.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}
It is with great sadness that we announce the death of Professor Lamin Sanneh on January 6, 2019.  
Sanneh served on the charter Advisory Council of the DACB that began in 1995 and, in recent years, he was a member of the Editorial Committee. When I received the news of his death Monday morning, I was overwhelmed with a terrible feeling of loss. The article I was editing was full of references to his work. His name appears on many pages of the DACB website. The sight of his name on the spines of the books surrounding me suddenly brought a sense of grief that remains with me. I will always remember his guidance, wisdom, and encouragement in my work for the DACB. The community of scholars in Africa and the West will feel the loss of his light for years to come.   
Below are a few tributes in his memory from DACB Editors and Advisors.  

**Michele Sigg, DACB Associate Director and JACB Managing Editor**

*Photo: Lamin Sanneh and Andrew Walls, charter Advisory Council members (date of the photo: 2003)
Credit: Rev. Dan Nicholas*.


**Jonathan Bonk, director of the *Dictionary of African Christian Biography*, Center for Global Christianity and Mission at Boston University**:

I first met Lamin in 1979 at the University of Aberdeen, where I was studying under Andrew Walls. Lamin, recently graduated from the School of African and Oriental Studies (SOAS) at London University with a PhD in Islamic History, had been recruited by Walls to fill a gap in the Department of Religious Studies. To Lamin’s surprise, a year after arriving he was “invited” to teach the required seminar on Christianity as a World Religion. He was too polite to decline … and the rest is history.

He was gripped by the phenomenon of contemporary Christianity as a primarily non-Western religion. He became one of the best informed and most trusted interpreters of world Christianity and Islam of his generation. As comfortable with some of Islam’s most gifted intellectuals as he was with Christians in the upper echelons of ecclesiology and academia, his deeply informed understanding of and appreciate for both faiths combined with his modesty and his eloquence to make him a unique and much sought after voice in an era more characterized by reductionist polarizations than by deep understanding.

A committed Christian, Lamin understood and appreciated his Muslim roots. His last major book—*Beyond Jihad: The Pacifist Tradition in West African Islam* (OUP 2016)—had, he told me over Turkish lunch, left him intellectually and physically exhausted. It was, he thought, his magnum opus, and he doubted that he would attempt another one.

Physically, he was an imposing figure; intellectually, he was even more impressive. These qualities were combined with deep personal modesty and a willingness to listen carefully to what others had to say. One of my favorite experiences for many years was his summation at the end of each annual Yale-Edinburgh Group on the History of Missionary Movement and World Christianity meeting, now anticipating its 29th year.

Lamin was fond of pointing out that those who gathered were simply a group of friends from around the world who shared a common academic interest and who gathered alternative years at the University of Edinburgh and Yale University to read papers, discuss issues, share points-of-view, and encourage each other. At the end of these two and a half day marathons--in which Lamin inevitably sat in the front row deep in thought, with his eyes closed--he would provide an eloquent verbatim summary of the event, respectfully referencing every presentation and its author, knitting the disparate pieces together into a picture that was better than we knew!

And now my good friend is home at last—summoned from the margins to the Center. He is sorely missed.

Source: [*Christianity Today International*, January 8, 2019](https://www.christianitytoday.com/news/2019/january/lamin-sanneh-died-world-christianity-islam-africa-yale.html)


**Dana L. Robert, director of the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at Boston University School of Theology; Editorial Committee, *Dictionary of African Christian Biography***:

Professor Lamin Sanneh was a giant in the field of World Christianity. His loss sends a tidal wave across multiple fields, institutions, and continents. He will be sorely missed by those of us who worked with him and called him friend, as well as by people who knew him only from his powerful writings.

As an African, a superb scholar, and a convert from Islam, Lamin Sanneh saw from the outside what those raised on the inside could not. His 1989 book *Translating the Message* showed how the gospel could become part of every culture, through being translated into the language and worldview of the people. He challenged the assumption that Christianity was merely a tool of western colonizers.

Through his founding of the annual Yale-Edinburgh conferences on mission history, his publications, his editorship of the Oxford University Press World Christianity Series, his leadership of the *Dictionary of African Christian Biography*, and many other important projects, Lamin Sanneh collaborated with others to transform the study of mission history, African religions, and World Christianity.

Source: [*Christianity Today International*, January 8, 2019](https://www.christianitytoday.com/news/2019/january/lamin-sanneh-died-world-christianity-islam-africa-yale.html)


**Philomena Njeri Mwaura, Director, Centre for Gender Equity and Empowerment; Associate Professor, Department of Philosophy and Religious Studies, Kenyatta University; DACB Advisory Council member**

What a tragedy!  I have received the news of the passing of Prof Sanneh with great shock and sadness! I have no words to say to his family, colleagues and friends. His passing is a great loss to the African academic fraternity and globally. I had the privilege to meet him severally in New Haven and at the conference on African Christian Biography sometimes back in Boston. He will always be remembered because of his ground breaking work on African Christianity. May the Lord comfort his family and give them the strength to bear this great loss. Fare thee well Prof. Sanneh.

(Source: email dated January 8, 2019)

**Jesse Mugambi,  Ecumenist; World Council of Churches; Professor of Philosophy and Religious Studies, University of Nairobi, Kenya; DACB Advisory Council member**

Lamin Sanneh [was] one of the most admirable role-models for African Academia—-both within our continent and among the African diaspora in Europe and North America. His death has come only a few months after that of Professor James H. Cone on 28th April 2018. As we mourn these great scholars, the greatest and most worthwhile tributes with which to honor them, will be our own endeavor to emulate them— each of us in our respective specializations and vocations, especially the published works of Lamin Sanneh and James H. Cone.

(Source: email dated January 7, 2019)

**Esther E. Acolatse, associate professor of pastoral theology and intercultural studies at Knox College at the University of Toronto; DACB Advisory Council member**:

I’m overwhelmed with sadness even as I recall fond memories of Professor Lamin Sanneh … This past year has been enriched by his astute mind and generosity to a younger colleague. I was pleasantly surprised by his thoughtful engagement of my work in a foreword to my latest book and an extended conversation with him in April as well as November where it was clear he still had a lot to contribute to the shaping of the field of global Christianity and its tenor.

He shared a couple of devotions he had authored for *The Christian Century* in 1989 and suggested that we could write and make such devotions available to the African Church and beyond. Those devotions coupled with his vast academic writing brought me face to face with the mind and spiritual life behind it.

When I asked how he found time to write so much. He simply said: &quot;Because I’m afraid one day I’ll be asked by God to give account of how I have used my time. I want to be able to bear up under that question.&quot;&quot; Just less than a month ago, we communicated as he waited to board a plane from Accra, and his hopes for my involvement with the new center just named for him. Now, labor over, he joins the church triumphant. His works and the many lives he has touched will continue to bear testimony to a life faithfully lived.

Source: [*Christianity Today International*, January 8, 2019](https://www.christianitytoday.com/news/2019/january/lamin-sanneh-died-world-christianity-islam-africa-yale.html)



Other tributes by John Azumah, J. Kwabena Asamoah-Gyadu, Joel Carpenter, and Edith Blumhofer can be found at [*Christianity Today International*, January 8, 2019](https://www.christianitytoday.com/news/2019/january/lamin-sanneh-died-world-christianity-islam-africa-yale.html)


**Tributes collected from DACB readers and associates.**

A recognized pioneer in the exploding interdisciplinary field of World Christianity, Lamin was a rare scholar who combined rhetorical eloquence with scholarly erudition, and religious conviction with child-like curiosity. Arguing, for example, that the missionary movement's greatest gift to the peoples of the world was Bible translation, he sought to free us from our presuppositions and hubris, saying, &quot;It is not so much that the West transmitted the gospel to world but that the cultures of the world discovered the gospel when they heard the Bible in their mother tongues.&quot; This profound insight from a convert from Islam into the intrinsic and infinite translatability of the gospel still has not been understood or heeded by much of the Western theological academy. (...) In the past thirty years, there is hardly a dissertation in the fields of Missiology, World Christianity, Missional Theology, or Intercultural Theology that fails to reference Sanneh’s work.  
  -From the [Overseas Ministries Study Center website](https://www.omsc.org/news/2019/1/18/in-memoriam)


Oh no! What a loss to the global church and the global church community. Three years ago, I spent the most beautiful time with Prof Sanneh at a workshop organised by Calvin College’s the Nagel Institute in Kenya.

Once every 50 years a theologian comes along whose contribution is so profound that the course of a discipline is changed. Sanneh was one such a scholar. Few scholars have highlighted African agency and Africa’s contribution to world Christianity as incisively and insightfully as Lamin Sanneh.

Tinyiko Maluleke

*(Source: email dated 1/8/2019)*


May his soul rest in peace and rise in glory.

africanchurch@gmail.com

*(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)*


What a sad news!
The death of an exceptional person leaves a terrible void but also a considerable moral legacy. We are carriers of this flame that Prof. Lamin Sanneh lit in our hearts ... We are custodians of his memory. We will never forget him and he will live forever.
May the Lord comfort his family, institutions, and friends.
May his soul rest in peace.
Best Regards,
Priscille

Rev. Prof. Priscille Djomhoué

Professeur de Nouveau Testament
Faculté Universitaire de Théologie Protestante
Rue des Bollandistes 40, B-1040 Bruxelles

*(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)*


Oh Lord have mercy. I just made reference to him this afternoon. Very shocked at the news. May his soul rest in peace. My deepest condolences to his family.

Korku Laryea

*(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)*


It is with deep sadness that Prof. Lamin Sanneh has transited prematurelly. His Sterling contribution in the development and growth of the Dictionary of African Biography will remain as a monument in the llife and work of DACB. My sincere condolences to DACB and to his family.
Silas

Very Rev. Prof. Silas Ncozana
Chuluchosema Pastor
P.O. Box 5115 Limbe
Tel. No. 0888377732
Malawi

*(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)*


To: The Family and Friends of Late Prof. Lamin Sanneh

Re: TRIBUTE TO LATE PROFESSOR LAMIN SANNEH

The news of the demise of Prof. Lamin Sanneh came to me as a rude shock. We are missing a member of the intelligesia, Prof. Lamin Sanneh was a legend and a humble researcher full of love, strength and encouragement. We shall never forget your contributions to the theological community. May your gentle soul rest in perfect peace, and may God grant us all the fortitude to bear this great loss.

His Holiness, The Most Revd. Dr. Rufus Okikiola OSITELU (PhD Computer Science; PhD Religious Studies);  Aladura Patriarch &amp; Primate of The Church of the Lord (Prayer Fellowship) Worldwide [TCLPFW] a.k.a TCLAW;  P. O. Box 71, Shagamu;10/12 Primate Ositelu Street;  Ogere-Remo; Ogun State, Nigeria, West Africa; Tel.: +234-803-7263902;      +234-803-0850226;       +234-816-588-5990; cla.primate@gmail.com;  cla_primate@yahoo.com;  cla_primate@hotmail.com;  www.aladura.net   /   www.tclpfw.org   /   www.tclaw.org  /  www.the-church-of-the-lord-aladura-worldwide.org

*(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)*


The Demise of Prof. Lamin Sanneh:

What a sad news to begin the new year with!
With the demise of Prof. Sanneh, Africa has  lost one of his most committed scholars and theologians of interreligious and intercultural dialogue. In all his writings, lectures and inter-personal and communal encounters, Prof. Sanneh always brought with him his  magnanimous spirit. This is most apparent in all his works and writings from an African perspective  on the North-South dialogue. You just need to take up and read his ,&quot;Whose Religion is Christianity&quot;, or his magnus opus, &quot;Translating the Message&quot;, and above all his master-piece author-biography, &quot;Summoned from the Margin: Homecoming of An African.&quot;

Prof. Sanneh has been a great source of inspiration and model to many young African theologians. My consolation here is that through my suggestion, some of my students had written their dissertations, even up to doctorate on the thoughts of Lamin Sanneh, especially on the subjects of intercultural encounters and translating the message. Furthermore, the life experience, his religious and conversion journey of Prof. Sanneh, from Islam to Christianity, and from one Christian denomination to another singled him out as a unique figure and man of faith.

My condolences to his wife and children, and also to his academic family at the Yale University, and numerous students, friends and acquaintances.

With the demise of Lamin Sanneh, Africa has lost one of his greatest scholars and theologians of the 20th and 21st centuries. May God receive his good soul and strengthen his family he has left.

Text of tribute by Fr. Oborji, [&quot;Lamin Sanneh: A Foremost African Theologian from the Gambia&quot;--PDF file](/resources/bio-pdfs/gambia/sanneh-lamin1.pdf)

Fr. Francis Anekwe Oborji
(Professor Ordinarius of contextual theology, Pontifical Urbaniana University, Rome)

*(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)*


This is indeed sad news to hear. We have indeed lost an academic giant. I was fortunate to get one of his famous books &quot;Translating the Message,&quot; through your inspiration. I will keep him in my prayers as well as his family and well-wishers he left behind. Thank you for this information as usual. May God continue to bless you with more wisdom and good health. Have a wonderful new year!
Fr. Fred.

FR. CHIMA FREDRICK MBIERE, BA, PH.D.
Resurrection Parish
410 Anne Street
PO Box 47 Illiopolis,
IL 62539-0047, USA

*(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)*


It is sad to learn of the death of Prof.Sanneh. His contributions to this monumental task of DACB will  live to pay him greater tribute. May the good Lord reward him with eternal life.

Paul Nchoji Nkwi, DACB Advisory Council

*(Source: email dated 1/9/2019)*


I am sorry for the loss of Lamim Sanneh. May God receive him in His glory and support his family.

Bishop Pierre-Claver Ngezahayo
Eglise Wesleyenne du Burundi

*(Source: email dated 1/10/2019)*


We pray for you all to be comforted of the Lord in this loss.
May his soul rest in peace.

With Regards,
From Africa Brotherhood Church

*(Source: email dated 1/10/2019)*


Thank you for sending me this sad news.  I remember several presentations made of the significance of Christ to Muslims.
His death is a great loss to us.
I hope I will be back from church in time to hear part of his funeral service.

Yours sincerely,
Russell Staples

*(Source: email dated 1/10/2019)*

Dear Prof. O.,
I just finished reading your mail announcing to me the demise of an African academic giant, Prof. Lamin Sanneh.  Thanks for the information. It's really sad that we (Africa)  and indeed the world has lost such a special gift to humanity.
I thank you immensely for directing me to the world of the thoughts of Prof.  Lamin Sanneh for both my Licentiate and Doctorate. His works are naturally revolutionary and compelling in character. His boldness and clarity of thought are disarming and endearing.
May God grant him eternal rest and console his immediate family in particular and his academic family in general.

Ferdinand Ndubuisi Okoli
Christ the King Parish Amata Mgbowo,  Enugu, Nigeria.  

*(Source: email dated 1/11/2019)*


Tribute to Professor Lamin Sanneh

My first introduction to Professor Lamin Sanneh was at New College, Edinburgh in 1991.  Professor Andrew Walls had invited Lamin Sanneh for a series of lectures geared towards a small group of us involved in the Study of Christianity in the Non-Western World.  Lamin skillfully opened blinders that limited my vision of God’s Great Kingdom in the world.  And then in 2006, during Lila’s and my six month stint at OMSC, we had occasion to fraternise with Lamin a number of times.  What impressed me about this “giant of a scholar” was his humility, his probing questions, his boisterous laughter, and his disarming manner of pricking the balloons of western missionaries who had a penchant for taking ourselves too seriously.  Lamin Sanneh, together with Andrew Walls, played a significant role in steering my doctoral research towards the history and rich narratives of hundreds of indigenous evangelists who valiantly proclaimed the Jesus story in southern Ethiopia.

E. Paul Balisky (PhD)

*(Source: email dated 1/12/2019)*


Allow me to give my heart felt condolences.
Human days are like a burning candle, at one moment in time the candle will burn out. It was with great sadness that news of the demise of the son of Africa reached us.
Surely like writing in the sand our lives are just as brief memory which fades with time.
From my understanding, death is not the end. I thank God for the many writings Lamin has inspired many, we give tribute for the work and life despite the challenges of life , with all its turns and twist I thank God that This great Son of Africa has influenced and touched us.
The demise indeed  is a great loss especially to his family and wiring fraternity.
For those who knew Lamin personally, forever in your hearts fond memories with great love will never be erased.
RIP
Yours, Kabīrū Fredrick

*(Source: email dated 1/14/2019*

I was saddened to hear about the sudden death of Professor Lamin Sanneh a very distinguished son of Africa. We shall all miss him but we thank God for the phenomenal contribution he made to the history of Christianity in Africa and beyond and we pray that his should should rest in peace and that God should grant him a crown of glory. Our prayers go to his family and relatives.

James Amanze, DACB Advisory Council

*(Source: email dated 1/14/2019)*


The late Prof Sanneh, will be dearly missed.  He has however left an important legacy for us all.  My wish is that his family and all his loved ones will find God’s grace sufficient to carry them/us during this taxing moment.

Madipoane Masenya, DACB Advisory Council

*(Source: email dated 1/15/2019)*


 We thank God for the life and service of Laminah Sanneh. May God encourage and comfort his family.

Edison Kalengyo, DACB Advisory Council

*(Source: email dated 1/15/2019)*</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It is with great sadness that we announce the death of Professor Lamin Sanneh on January 6, 2019. Sanneh served on the charter Advisory Council of the DACB that began in 1995 and, in recent years, he was a member of the Editorial Committee. When I received the news of his death Monday morning, I was overwhelmed with a terrible feeling of loss. The article I was editing was full of references to his work. His name appears on many pages of the DACB website. The sight of his name on the spines of the books surrounding me suddenly brought a sense of grief that remains with me. I will always remember his guidance, wisdom, and encouragement in my work for the DACB. The community of scholars in Africa and the West will feel the loss of his light for years to come. Below are a few tributes in his memory from DACB Editors and Advisors.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Release of African Christian Biography Volume</title><link href="/ACB-VOLUME/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release of African Christian Biography Volume" /><published>2018-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/ACB-VOLUME</id><content type="html" xml:base="/ACB-VOLUME/">![ACB Volume](/images/news/acbvolume2018.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}
**Cluster Publications** of South Africa has just released *African Christian Biography*, edited by Dana L. Robert, a volume of the proceedings of the African Christian Biography Conference held at Boston University in October 2015.

**About this book**:
The papers in this volume narrate the histories of leading African Christians, and reflect on the meaning of writing African Christian biographies. Written to celebrate the *Dictionary of African Christian Biography* (www.dacb.org), this volume shows why remembering the lives of Christian leaders remains important for understanding African history, Christian identities, and African contributions to the shaping of World Christianity. The authors include some of the world’s leading scholars of African Christianity in its social, political, and theological contexts. Subjects of the papers range from an Ethiopian saint, to kings and queens, history making Protestant pastors, and women whose hidden stories undergird their transformative
leadership of family, church and society.

You may view or download:
 [Table of Contents](/resources/ACB-volume-index.pdf)
 [Promotional flier](/resources/ACB-volume-flier.pdf)</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Cluster Publications of South Africa has just released African Christian Biography, edited by Dana L. Robert, a volume of the proceedings of the African Christian Biography Conference held at Boston University in October 2015.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">DACB Advisory Council Meeting: October 6-9, 2017</title><link href="/DACB-advisory-meeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DACB Advisory Council Meeting: October 6-9, 2017" /><published>2017-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/DACB-advisory-meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DACB-advisory-meeting/">![Trinity Orthodox Church](/images/news/orth-church2017.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}The DACB Advisory Council meeting was held October 6-9, 2017 in Nairobi, Kenya at the St. Mary Magdalene Retreat Center, located at Resurrection Gardens. This year, we had the joy of welcoming from Cameroon Professor Paul Nkwi who had not been able to join us in previous years due to visa problems. The group attended Sunday worship service at Trinity Orthodox Church. One focus of the discussions was the promotion and distribution of the *Journal of African Christian Biography* in African institutions.</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The DACB Advisory Council meeting was held October 6-9, 2017 in Nairobi, Kenya at the St. Mary Magdalene Retreat Center, located at Resurrection Gardens. This year, we had the joy of welcoming from Cameroon Professor Paul Nkwi who had not been able to join us in previous years due to visa problems. The group attended Sunday worship service at Trinity Orthodox Church. One focus of the discussions was the promotion and distribution of the Journal of African Christian Biography in African institutions.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Complete Redesign of DACB Website</title><link href="/new-site/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Complete Redesign of DACB Website" /><published>2017-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/new-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="/new-site/">This summer, the DACB website underwent a complete redesign using a flat-file CMS system conceived by leading software development platform Github. The new site has a lightweight digital footprint, loads fast, and can be distributed on USB drives in areas without Internet access. In addition, multiple indexes and a powerful standalone search engine (that works offline) make it easy to do in-depth research on the site.

Indexing of subjects (as catechists, martyrs, etc) is still underway and will hopefully be completed by November. Please do not hesitate to contact us at [dacb@bu.edu](mailto:dacb@bu.edu) if you see anything that needs correcting.</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This summer, the DACB website underwent a complete redesign using a flat-file CMS system conceived by leading software development platform Github. The new site has a lightweight digital footprint, loads fast, and can be distributed on USB drives in areas without Internet access. In addition, multiple indexes and a powerful standalone search engine (that works offline) make it easy to do in-depth research on the site.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Resources for Research: Newly Redesigned Website for Old &amp;amp; New in Shona at Boston University</title><link href="/shona-new/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resources for Research: Newly Redesigned Website for Old &amp; New in Shona at Boston University" /><published>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/shona-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="/shona-new/">The [website](http://sites.bu.edu/shonareligion/) is the fruit of about 6 years of work by graduate students from the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at BU who scanned roughly 1,200 of Dr. Inus Daneel’s photographs of life among the AICs and Traditionalists from the 1960s on.

Here is a sample 4-minute audio slide narrated by Daneel:  

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K5jqsi9qzsM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The website is the fruit of about 6 years of work by graduate students from the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at BU who scanned roughly 1,200 of Dr. Inus Daneel’s photographs of life among the AICs and Traditionalists from the 1960s on.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Protestantism has changed in 500 years!</title><link href="/protestantism-has-changed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Protestantism has changed in 500 years!" /><published>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/protestantism-has-changed</id><content type="html" xml:base="/protestantism-has-changed/">![](http://www.dacb.org/resources/500-Prots-CSGC.gif){: .bio}From the _Center for the Study of Global Christianity_ (Gordon-Conwell):

For several centuries the Protestant movement was based in Europe, and then North America. In 2017 there are 560 million Protestants found in nearly all the world’s 234 countries. Of these 560 million, only 16% are in Europe, but 41% are in Africa. We anticipate by 2050, 53% of all Protestants will live in Africa.  

Download the free infographic from the CSGC [here](http://www.gordonconwell.edu/ockenga/research/Resources-and-Downloads.cfm).</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">From the Center for the Study of Global Christianity (Gordon-Conwell):</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Conference Overview: African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries</title><link href="/conference-overview/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conference Overview: African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries" /><published>2015-10-01T15:34:41-04:00</published><updated>2015-10-01T15:34:41-04:00</updated><id>/conference-overview</id><content type="html" xml:base="/conference-overview/">![Conference-Panel](/images/news/confer-panel.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}The Center for Global Christianity and Mission at Boston University hosted the conference on the theme of “African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries,” from Thursday, October 29 to Saturday, October 31. Approximately sixty scholars and graduate students converged on the School of Theology from Nigeria, Zimbabwe, Kenya, Ghana, Great Britain, and various universities in the United States and Canada to present papers and discuss issues on the theme of African Christian Biography. As an intersection between scholars in religious studies and African studies, the conference was a venue for cross-fertilization between the various fields represented. Furthermore, it was an opportunity to celebrate the twentieth anniversary of the Dictionary of African Christian Biography (DACB).

![Conference-Panel](/images/news/confer-reception.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}In the opening plenary, DACB Project Director Jonathan Bonk presented a brief historical overview by looking at the “What?, the Why?, the How?, and the Now What?” of the project. In the Friday morning plenary address, Prof. Lamin Sanneh of Yale University focused his talk on Sir Samuel Lewis whose extraordinary life illustrated the power of human example in the service of religion and society in 19th century West Africa. The afternoon plenary panel with noted scholars Kathleen Sheldon, Richard Elphick, and Diana Wylie addressed, among other questions, the challenge of the portrayal of belief in biography as well as the various uses of biography in historical writing. The dinner plenary by Boston University professor Linda Heywood offered an opportunity to explore the life of a notable 17th century Kongo figure, Queen Njinga.

In the concurrent sessions, questions raised either in the papers or in the subsequent discussion included the role of biography in pedagogy, orality and memory in biography, the use of photography and film in biography, and the use of biography for highlighting the stories of women the Global South. Almost a third of the papers examined the stories of African women, exploring their roles as helpers and leaders, most often unrecognized in the historical record. The discussions also looked at the role of biographers as portrait artists who must paint their subjects with humility and empathy.

![Conference-Dinner](/images/news/confer-dinner.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}In the closing session, the progress of the DACB was praised and many participants offered ideas and challenges for new developments in the future. Conference organizer Dana Robert offered a few words about the book that will be published as a fruit of the conference.

View the [ACB Conference booklet]({{site.url}}/resources/ACBprogram2015.pdf).</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Center for Global Christianity and Mission at Boston University hosted the conference on the theme of “African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries,” from Thursday, October 29 to Saturday, October 31. Approximately sixty scholars and graduate students converged on the School of Theology from Nigeria, Zimbabwe, Kenya, Ghana, Great Britain, and various universities in the United States and Canada to present papers and discuss issues on the theme of African Christian Biography. As an intersection between scholars in religious studies and African studies, the conference was a venue for cross-fertilization between the various fields represented. Furthermore, it was an opportunity to celebrate the twentieth anniversary of the Dictionary of African Christian Biography (DACB).</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Conference Information and Schedule</title><link href="/conference-schedule/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conference Information and Schedule" /><published>2015-10-01T15:34:41-04:00</published><updated>2015-10-01T15:34:41-04:00</updated><id>/conference-schedule</id><content type="html" xml:base="/conference-schedule/">**“African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries”**
**Boston University, October 29-31**
**General Information**
**October 29-31, 2015**

_Note: The opening reception, the Friday morning plenary, and the Friday afternoon panel are open to non-registrants. Meals (including plenaries at the meals) are open to fully registered participants only. This is a working conference._  

_Thursday, Oct 29_  

2:00 – 4:00 Registration in African Studies library, Mugar Memorial Library  

4:00 - 5:30 Opening reception at the African Studies library; exhibits - OPEN SESSION  

Welcome by Dana Robert, Center for Global Christianity and Mission; Beth Restrick, African Studies Library; Jonathan Bonk, Dictionary of African Christian Biography  

5:30 – 7:30 Dinner for registrants, discussion of conference details  

**Project plenary, Jon Bonk, _African Church History and the Streetlight Effect: Biography as A Lost Key_**  

_Friday, Oct 30_  

9:00 – 10:00 **Morning plenary: Lamin Sanneh, _Biography and the Narrative of History_** _- OPEN SESSION_  
10:00 – 10:30 Coffee break  

10:30 – 12:30 Concurrent Paper Sessions  

1.A. _Early Biography_. Bishop Graham Kings, chair  

**Michael Glerup, _The Life of Paul of Thebes and the Living Memory of Contemporary African Communities._  

Wendy Belcher, _The Life and Visions of Krəstos Śämra, a Fifteenth-Century Ethiopian Female Saint._  

John Thornton, _King Afonso of Kongo_**  

1.B. Biography as historical narrative: Chris Evans, chair  

**Mark Noll, _Mizeki, Chilembwe, Harris and the Future of African Christianity in its Past_  

**

**Stan Chu Ilo, _The Stories My Grand Parents Never Told Me: Memory and Orality in the Narrative of African Christian History_**

**Michele Sigg_, Narrative as History: African Christian Biography as History in the Dictionary of African Christian Biography_**  

12:30 – 2:00 Lunch  

2:00 - 3:30 **Panel: Tim Longman, chair—_Biography as History  
_  
Panelists: Kathleen Sheldon, Diana Wylie, Richard Elphick** - OPEN SESSION  

3:30 - 4:00 Coffee break  

4:00 - 5:45 Concurrent Paper Sessions.  

2.A. _Critical perspectives on South African biography._ Diana Wylie, chair.  

**Joanne Davis, _Omission and Elision: Missing the Target in Biographies of the Reverend Tiyo Soga_  

Deborah Gaitskell, _Preaching as Boxing? The Sermons of Seth Mokitimi, the ‘Brown Bomber,’ as a Biographical Resource_  

Roger Levine, _Jan Tzatzoe or Dyani Tshatshu: Personal, Political, and Historical Consequences of Naming in African History_**  
2.B. _Women in South Africa and Zimbabwe_. Dana Robert, Chair.  

**Heather Hughes, _Recovering the Lives of Early African Women Christians in South Africa: The Case of Nokutela Dube_  

Barbara Mahamba, _A Character Worth Writing About: Roman Catholic Girls and Women’s Education Mirrored through the Experiences of Sikhaulaphi Khumalo_  

Wendy Urban-Mead, _&quot;Ah, if only Nellie could be ordained&quot;: The Leadership and Witness of Nellie Maduma Mlotshwa, Zimbabwe 1958 to 2015_**  
6:00 – 8:00 Dinner and Plenary (Castle)  

**Linda Heywood, _Queen Njinga of Angola: Spirituality and Politics_  
**  

_Saturday, Oct 31_  

9:00 -11:00 Concurrent Paper Sessions  

3.A. African Christian Biography in Ghana/West Africa. Nimi Wariboko, chair  

**Ethan R. Sanders, _James Aggrey and the Movement of Political Thought in Africa_**  

**Maureen Iheanacho, _Unknown Pioneers and Unsung Heroes: Forgotten Christian Ancestors of the Gold Coast (Ghana)_**  

3.B. Methods, theories, and models for African biography. Jean-Luc Enyegue, chair  

**Paul Grant, _Biography as Counter-Narrative to Rupture: The Moral Problem of Describing Intact Lives_**  

**The Most Rev Emmanuel A.S. Egbunu, _Towards Authentic Characterization in African Christian Biography_**  

**Philomena Mwaura, _Gender and Power in African Christian Biography_**  

11:00-11:15 Coffee break  

11:15 - 1:00 Project Wrap up and Boxed lunch  

Over lunch a panel of “listeners’” will offer a response to the conference and there will be an open discussion. Panelists are **Andrew Barnes, Joel Carpenter, and Jacob Olupona**</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries” Boston University, October 29-31 General Information October 29-31, 2015</summary></entry></feed>