<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-08-17T15:17:16-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Dictionary of African Christian Biography</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Resources for Research: Newly Redesigned Website for Old &amp;amp; New in Shona at Boston University</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/shona-new/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resources for Research: Newly Redesigned Website for Old &amp; New in Shona at Boston University" /><published>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/shona-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/shona-new/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://sites.bu.edu/shonareligion/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; is the fruit of about 6 years of work by graduate students from the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at BU who scanned roughly 1,200 of Dr. Inus Daneel’s photographs of life among the AICs and Traditionalists from the 1960s on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a sample 4-minute audio slide narrated by Daneel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;280&quot; height=&quot;157&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K5jqsi9qzsM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The website is the fruit of about 6 years of work by graduate students from the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at BU who scanned roughly 1,200 of Dr. Inus Daneel’s photographs of life among the AICs and Traditionalists from the 1960s on.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Protestantism has changed in 500 years!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/protestantism-has-changed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Protestantism has changed in 500 years!" /><published>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/protestantism-has-changed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/protestantism-has-changed/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.dacb.org/resources/500-Prots-CSGC.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;bio&quot; /&gt;From the &lt;em&gt;Center for the Study of Global Christianity&lt;/em&gt; (Gordon-Conwell):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For several centuries the Protestant movement was based in Europe, and then North America. In 2017 there are 560 million Protestants found in nearly all the world’s 234 countries. Of these 560 million, only 16% are in Europe, but 41% are in Africa. We anticipate by 2050, 53% of all Protestants will live in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the free infographic from the CSGC &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gordonconwell.edu/ockenga/research/Resources-and-Downloads.cfm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">From the Center for the Study of Global Christianity (Gordon-Conwell):</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/african-christian-biography/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries" /><published>2017-05-17T15:34:41-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-17T15:34:41-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/african-christian-biography</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/african-christian-biography/">&lt;p&gt;The Center for Global Christianity and Mission at Boston University hosted the conference on the theme of “African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries,” from Thursday, October 29 to Saturday, October 31. Approximately sixty scholars and graduate students converged on the School of Theology from Nigeria, Zimbabwe, Kenya, Ghana, Great Britain, and various universities in the United States and Canada to present papers and discuss issues on the theme of African Christian Biography. As an intersection between scholars in religious studies and African studies, the conference was a venue for cross-fertilization between the various fields represented. Furthermore, it was an opportunity to celebrate the twentieth anniversary of the Dictionary of African Christian Biography (DACB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the opening plenary, DACB Project Director Jonathan Bonk presented a brief historical overview by looking at the “What?, the Why?, the How?, and the Now What?” of the project. In the Friday morning plenary address, Prof. Lamin Sanneh of Yale University focused his talk on Sir Samuel Lewis whose extraordinary life illustrated the power of human example in the service of religion and society in 19th century West Africa. The afternoon plenary panel with noted scholars Kathleen Sheldon, Richard Elphick, and Diana Wylie addressed, among other questions, the challenge of the portrayal of belief in biography as well as the various uses of biography in historical writing. The dinner plenary by Boston University professor Linda Heywood offered an opportunity to explore the life of a notable 17th century Kongo figure, Queen Njinga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the concurrent sessions, questions raised either in the papers or in the subsequent discussion included the role of biography in pedagogy, orality and memory in biography, the use of photography and film in biography, and the use of biography for highlighting the stories of women the Global South. Almost a third of the papers examined the stories of African women, exploring their roles as helpers and leaders, most often unrecognized in the historical record. The discussions also looked at the role of biographers as portrait artists who must paint their subjects with humility and empathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the closing session, the progress of the DACB was praised and many participants offered ideas and challenges for new developments in the future. Conference organizer Dana Robert offered a few words about the book that will be published as a fruit of the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View the &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/resources/ACBprogram2015.pdf&quot;&gt;ACB Conference booklet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Center for Global Christianity and Mission at Boston University hosted the conference on the theme of “African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries,” from Thursday, October 29 to Saturday, October 31. Approximately sixty scholars and graduate students converged on the School of Theology from Nigeria, Zimbabwe, Kenya, Ghana, Great Britain, and various universities in the United States and Canada to present papers and discuss issues on the theme of African Christian Biography. As an intersection between scholars in religious studies and African studies, the conference was a venue for cross-fertilization between the various fields represented. Furthermore, it was an opportunity to celebrate the twentieth anniversary of the Dictionary of African Christian Biography (DACB).</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">CALL FOR PAPERS: “African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/callforpapers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CALL FOR PAPERS: “African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries”" /><published>2015-05-17T15:34:41-04:00</published><updated>2015-05-17T15:34:41-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/callforpapers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/callforpapers/">&lt;p&gt;October 29-31, 2015. Boston, Massachusetts. Sponsored by the &lt;em&gt;Dictionary of African Christian Biography&lt;/em&gt; (www.dacb.org ); the Center for Global Christianity and Mission (www.bu.edu/cgcm/), the African Studies Center (www.bu.edu/africa/), and the African Studies Library (www.bu.edu/library/african-studies/ ), Boston University. Keynote Speaker: Professor Lamin Sanneh, Yale University. Hosts: Professors Dana L. Robert, Jonathan Bonk, and M.L. Daneel, Boston University.
The writing of biography has become a major form of documentation for the growing world Christian movement. The purpose of this conference is to reflect upon the progress made by the first twenty years of the &lt;em&gt;Dictionary of African Christian Biography&lt;/em&gt;, the award-winning web-based documentation project founded in 1995, and to identify new directions in the use of biography and autobiography for the study of African Christianity. The goal of the conference is to produce an edited volume.&lt;br /&gt;
For those giving papers, travel and participation will be subsidized by the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at the Boston University School of Theology. The African Studies Library at Boston University will host a reception and special exhibits on the scholarship of African Christianity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requested paper topics include the following:&lt;br /&gt;
•	Narrative as history in the documentation of African Christianity&lt;br /&gt;
•	Biographies of African Christians&lt;br /&gt;
•	Multiple religious belonging in African church history&lt;br /&gt;
•	Women, gender, and the growth of African Christianity&lt;br /&gt;
•	Political and social dimensions of African Christian biography&lt;br /&gt;
•	Autobiography as history: possibilities and limitations&lt;br /&gt;
•	Hagiography as a tool for understanding African society, culture, and theology&lt;br /&gt;
•	Biographical research and writing: cultural and legal constraints on the research, use and interpretation of biography&lt;br /&gt;
•	African biography in World Christianity&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please send a one page description of the proposed topic and a brief vita to Ms. Michele Sigg, Project Manager, &lt;em&gt;Dictionary of African Christian Biography&lt;/em&gt; by Friday February 27, 2015. Email: dacb@bu.edu&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mailing address:&lt;br /&gt;
African Christian Biography Conference&lt;br /&gt;
Center for Global Christianity and Mission&lt;br /&gt;
Boston University School of Theology&lt;br /&gt;
745 Commonwealth Avenue&lt;br /&gt;
Boston, MA 02215&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">October 29-31, 2015. Boston, Massachusetts. Sponsored by the Dictionary of African Christian Biography (www.dacb.org ); the Center for Global Christianity and Mission (www.bu.edu/cgcm/), the African Studies Center (www.bu.edu/africa/), and the African Studies Library (www.bu.edu/library/african-studies/ ), Boston University. Keynote Speaker: Professor Lamin Sanneh, Yale University. Hosts: Professors Dana L. Robert, Jonathan Bonk, and M.L. Daneel, Boston University. The writing of biography has become a major form of documentation for the growing world Christian movement. The purpose of this conference is to reflect upon the progress made by the first twenty years of the Dictionary of African Christian Biography, the award-winning web-based documentation project founded in 1995, and to identify new directions in the use of biography and autobiography for the study of African Christianity. The goal of the conference is to produce an edited volume. For those giving papers, travel and participation will be subsidized by the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at the Boston University School of Theology. The African Studies Library at Boston University will host a reception and special exhibits on the scholarship of African Christianity.</summary></entry></feed>