<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-09-25T18:38:06-04:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Dictionary of African Christian Biography</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Resources for Research: Newly Redesigned Website for Old &amp;amp; New in Shona at Boston University</title><link href="/shona-new/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resources for Research: Newly Redesigned Website for Old &amp; New in Shona at Boston University" /><published>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/shona-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="/shona-new/">The [website](http://sites.bu.edu/shonareligion/) is the fruit of about 6 years of work by graduate students from the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at BU who scanned roughly 1,200 of Dr. Inus Daneel’s photographs of life among the AICs and Traditionalists from the 1960s on.

Here is a sample 4-minute audio slide narrated by Daneel:  

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K5jqsi9qzsM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The website is the fruit of about 6 years of work by graduate students from the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at BU who scanned roughly 1,200 of Dr. Inus Daneel’s photographs of life among the AICs and Traditionalists from the 1960s on.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Protestantism has changed in 500 years!</title><link href="/protestantism-has-changed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Protestantism has changed in 500 years!" /><published>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/protestantism-has-changed</id><content type="html" xml:base="/protestantism-has-changed/">![](http://www.dacb.org/resources/500-Prots-CSGC.gif){: .bio}From the _Center for the Study of Global Christianity_ (Gordon-Conwell):

For several centuries the Protestant movement was based in Europe, and then North America. In 2017 there are 560 million Protestants found in nearly all the world’s 234 countries. Of these 560 million, only 16% are in Europe, but 41% are in Africa. We anticipate by 2050, 53% of all Protestants will live in Africa.  

Download the free infographic from the CSGC [here](http://www.gordonconwell.edu/ockenga/research/Resources-and-Downloads.cfm).</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">From the Center for the Study of Global Christianity (Gordon-Conwell):</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Conference Overview: African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries</title><link href="/conference-overview/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conference Overview: African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries" /><published>2015-10-01T15:34:41-04:00</published><updated>2015-10-01T15:34:41-04:00</updated><id>/conference-overview</id><content type="html" xml:base="/conference-overview/">![Conference-Panel](/images/news/confer-panel.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}The Center for Global Christianity and Mission at Boston University hosted the conference on the theme of “African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries,” from Thursday, October 29 to Saturday, October 31. Approximately sixty scholars and graduate students converged on the School of Theology from Nigeria, Zimbabwe, Kenya, Ghana, Great Britain, and various universities in the United States and Canada to present papers and discuss issues on the theme of African Christian Biography. As an intersection between scholars in religious studies and African studies, the conference was a venue for cross-fertilization between the various fields represented. Furthermore, it was an opportunity to celebrate the twentieth anniversary of the Dictionary of African Christian Biography (DACB).

![Conference-Panel](/images/news/confer-reception.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}In the opening plenary, DACB Project Director Jonathan Bonk presented a brief historical overview by looking at the “What?, the Why?, the How?, and the Now What?” of the project. In the Friday morning plenary address, Prof. Lamin Sanneh of Yale University focused his talk on Sir Samuel Lewis whose extraordinary life illustrated the power of human example in the service of religion and society in 19th century West Africa. The afternoon plenary panel with noted scholars Kathleen Sheldon, Richard Elphick, and Diana Wylie addressed, among other questions, the challenge of the portrayal of belief in biography as well as the various uses of biography in historical writing. The dinner plenary by Boston University professor Linda Heywood offered an opportunity to explore the life of a notable 17th century Kongo figure, Queen Njinga.

In the concurrent sessions, questions raised either in the papers or in the subsequent discussion included the role of biography in pedagogy, orality and memory in biography, the use of photography and film in biography, and the use of biography for highlighting the stories of women the Global South. Almost a third of the papers examined the stories of African women, exploring their roles as helpers and leaders, most often unrecognized in the historical record. The discussions also looked at the role of biographers as portrait artists who must paint their subjects with humility and empathy.

![Conference-Dinner](/images/news/confer-dinner.jpg){:class=&quot;bio&quot;}In the closing session, the progress of the DACB was praised and many participants offered ideas and challenges for new developments in the future. Conference organizer Dana Robert offered a few words about the book that will be published as a fruit of the conference.

View the [ACB Conference booklet]({{site.url}}/resources/ACBprogram2015.pdf).</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Center for Global Christianity and Mission at Boston University hosted the conference on the theme of “African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries,” from Thursday, October 29 to Saturday, October 31. Approximately sixty scholars and graduate students converged on the School of Theology from Nigeria, Zimbabwe, Kenya, Ghana, Great Britain, and various universities in the United States and Canada to present papers and discuss issues on the theme of African Christian Biography. As an intersection between scholars in religious studies and African studies, the conference was a venue for cross-fertilization between the various fields represented. Furthermore, it was an opportunity to celebrate the twentieth anniversary of the Dictionary of African Christian Biography (DACB).</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Conference Information and Schedule</title><link href="/conference-schedule/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conference Information and Schedule" /><published>2015-10-01T15:34:41-04:00</published><updated>2015-10-01T15:34:41-04:00</updated><id>/conference-schedule</id><content type="html" xml:base="/conference-schedule/">**“African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries”**
**Boston University, October 29-31**
**General Information**
**October 29-31, 2015**

_Note: The opening reception, the Friday morning plenary, and the Friday afternoon panel are open to non-registrants. Meals (including plenaries at the meals) are open to fully registered participants only. This is a working conference._  

_Thursday, Oct 29_  

2:00 – 4:00 Registration in African Studies library, Mugar Memorial Library  

4:00 - 5:30 Opening reception at the African Studies library; exhibits - OPEN SESSION  

Welcome by Dana Robert, Center for Global Christianity and Mission; Beth Restrick, African Studies Library; Jonathan Bonk, Dictionary of African Christian Biography  

5:30 – 7:30 Dinner for registrants, discussion of conference details  

**Project plenary, Jon Bonk, _African Church History and the Streetlight Effect: Biography as A Lost Key_**  

_Friday, Oct 30_  

9:00 – 10:00 **Morning plenary: Lamin Sanneh, _Biography and the Narrative of History_** _- OPEN SESSION_  
10:00 – 10:30 Coffee break  

10:30 – 12:30 Concurrent Paper Sessions  

1.A. _Early Biography_. Bishop Graham Kings, chair  

**Michael Glerup, _The Life of Paul of Thebes and the Living Memory of Contemporary African Communities._  

Wendy Belcher, _The Life and Visions of Krəstos Śämra, a Fifteenth-Century Ethiopian Female Saint._  

John Thornton, _King Afonso of Kongo_**  

1.B. Biography as historical narrative: Chris Evans, chair  

**Mark Noll, _Mizeki, Chilembwe, Harris and the Future of African Christianity in its Past_  

**

**Stan Chu Ilo, _The Stories My Grand Parents Never Told Me: Memory and Orality in the Narrative of African Christian History_**

**Michele Sigg_, Narrative as History: African Christian Biography as History in the Dictionary of African Christian Biography_**  

12:30 – 2:00 Lunch  

2:00 - 3:30 **Panel: Tim Longman, chair—_Biography as History  
_  
Panelists: Kathleen Sheldon, Diana Wylie, Richard Elphick** - OPEN SESSION  

3:30 - 4:00 Coffee break  

4:00 - 5:45 Concurrent Paper Sessions.  

2.A. _Critical perspectives on South African biography._ Diana Wylie, chair.  

**Joanne Davis, _Omission and Elision: Missing the Target in Biographies of the Reverend Tiyo Soga_  

Deborah Gaitskell, _Preaching as Boxing? The Sermons of Seth Mokitimi, the ‘Brown Bomber,’ as a Biographical Resource_  

Roger Levine, _Jan Tzatzoe or Dyani Tshatshu: Personal, Political, and Historical Consequences of Naming in African History_**  
2.B. _Women in South Africa and Zimbabwe_. Dana Robert, Chair.  

**Heather Hughes, _Recovering the Lives of Early African Women Christians in South Africa: The Case of Nokutela Dube_  

Barbara Mahamba, _A Character Worth Writing About: Roman Catholic Girls and Women’s Education Mirrored through the Experiences of Sikhaulaphi Khumalo_  

Wendy Urban-Mead, _&quot;Ah, if only Nellie could be ordained&quot;: The Leadership and Witness of Nellie Maduma Mlotshwa, Zimbabwe 1958 to 2015_**  
6:00 – 8:00 Dinner and Plenary (Castle)  

**Linda Heywood, _Queen Njinga of Angola: Spirituality and Politics_  
**  

_Saturday, Oct 31_  

9:00 -11:00 Concurrent Paper Sessions  

3.A. African Christian Biography in Ghana/West Africa. Nimi Wariboko, chair  

**Ethan R. Sanders, _James Aggrey and the Movement of Political Thought in Africa_**  

**Maureen Iheanacho, _Unknown Pioneers and Unsung Heroes: Forgotten Christian Ancestors of the Gold Coast (Ghana)_**  

3.B. Methods, theories, and models for African biography. Jean-Luc Enyegue, chair  

**Paul Grant, _Biography as Counter-Narrative to Rupture: The Moral Problem of Describing Intact Lives_**  

**The Most Rev Emmanuel A.S. Egbunu, _Towards Authentic Characterization in African Christian Biography_**  

**Philomena Mwaura, _Gender and Power in African Christian Biography_**  

11:00-11:15 Coffee break  

11:15 - 1:00 Project Wrap up and Boxed lunch  

Over lunch a panel of “listeners’” will offer a response to the conference and there will be an open discussion. Panelists are **Andrew Barnes, Joel Carpenter, and Jacob Olupona**</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries” Boston University, October 29-31 General Information October 29-31, 2015</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">CALL FOR PAPERS: African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries</title><link href="/callforpapers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CALL FOR PAPERS: African Christian Biography: Narratives, Beliefs, and Boundaries" /><published>2015-05-17T15:34:41-04:00</published><updated>2015-05-17T15:34:41-04:00</updated><id>/callforpapers</id><content type="html" xml:base="/callforpapers/">October 29-31, 2015. Boston, Massachusetts. Sponsored by the *Dictionary of African Christian Biography*; the [Center for Global Christianity and Mission](http://www.bu.edu/cgcm/), the [African Studies Center](http://www.bu.edu/africa/), and the [African Studies Library](http://www.bu.edu/library/african-studies/), Boston University. Keynote Speaker: Professor Lamin Sanneh, Yale University. Hosts: Professors Dana L. Robert, Jonathan Bonk, and M.L. Daneel, Boston University.

The writing of biography has become a major form of documentation for the growing world Christian movement. The purpose of this conference is to reflect upon the progress made by the first twenty years of the _Dictionary of African Christian Biography_, the award-winning web-based documentation project founded in 1995, and to identify new directions in the use of biography and autobiography for the study of African Christianity. The goal of the conference is to produce an edited volume.

For those giving papers, travel and participation will be subsidized by the Center for Global Christianity and Mission at the Boston University School of Theology. The African Studies Library at Boston University will host a reception and special exhibits on the scholarship of African Christianity.  

Requested paper topics include the following:&lt;br/&gt;
•	Narrative as history in the documentation of African Christianity&lt;br/&gt;
•	Biographies of African Christians&lt;br/&gt;
•	Multiple religious belonging in African church history&lt;br/&gt;
•	Women, gender, and the growth of African Christianity&lt;br/&gt;
•	Political and social dimensions of African Christian biography&lt;br/&gt;
•	Autobiography as history: possibilities and limitations&lt;br/&gt;
•	Hagiography as a tool for understanding African society, culture, and theology&lt;br/&gt;
•	Biographical research and writing: cultural and legal constraints on the research, use and interpretation of biography&lt;br/&gt;
•	African biography in World Christianity&lt;br/&gt;

Please send a one page description of the proposed topic and a brief vita to Ms. Michele Sigg, Project Manager, _Dictionary of African Christian Biography_ by Friday February 27, 2015. Email: dacb@bu.edu&lt;br/&gt;

Mailing address:&lt;br/&gt;
African Christian Biography Conference&lt;br/&gt;
Center for Global Christianity and Mission&lt;br/&gt;
Boston University School of Theology&lt;br/&gt;
745 Commonwealth Avenue&lt;br/&gt;
Boston, MA 02215&lt;br/&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">October 29-31, 2015. Boston, Massachusetts. Sponsored by the Dictionary of African Christian Biography; the Center for Global Christianity and Mission, the African Studies Center, and the African Studies Library, Boston University. Keynote Speaker: Professor Lamin Sanneh, Yale University. Hosts: Professors Dana L. Robert, Jonathan Bonk, and M.L. Daneel, Boston University.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">New Developments!</title><link href="/new-developments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Developments!" /><published>2014-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2014-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/new-developments</id><content type="html" xml:base="/new-developments/">Since January of 2014, the DACB homepage and Web site have a new look. The main template now has new colors and a slightly modified design. The homepage has received a complete makeover in the interest of offering a more user-friendly experience to our readers. In order to highlight the many resources of the DACB, the new homepage now offers links to featured themes and articles on the Web site. In addition, the &quot;Research Resources&quot; box links to outside Web sites that can be of use to scholars of African Christianity (this includes missions and global Christianity as well). The content of these various boxes rotates on a weekly, semi-weekly, or monthly basis.

We recently added a new page for [Readers' Comments](/contribute/readers/). We welcome your feedback and your anecdotes or memories about people in the DACB. We share a selection of this feedback from our readers on this page. Please write us at [dacb@bu.edu](mailto:dacb@bu.edu).

More significant are the changes in the administrative structure of the DACB. There is now an [Editorial Committee](/about/editorial-committee/) that meets bi-annually for planning and a new [Advisory Council](/about/advisors/), composed of prominent African leaders either in academic institutions or in regional and continent-wide organizations related to the church and to theological education. For more news, please read our [January 2014 newsletter](/news/newsletter/).

Between January 1 and March 13, 2014, the DACB Web site received close to 90,000 unique visitors.</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Since January of 2014, the DACB homepage and Web site have a new look. The main template now has new colors and a slightly modified design. The homepage has received a complete makeover in the interest of offering a more user-friendly experience to our readers. In order to highlight the many resources of the DACB, the new homepage now offers links to featured themes and articles on the Web site. In addition, the “Research Resources” box links to outside Web sites that can be of use to scholars of African Christianity (this includes missions and global Christianity as well). The content of these various boxes rotates on a weekly, semi-weekly, or monthly basis.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">DACB Transfers to the Center For Global Christianity and Mission At Boston University School of Theology</title><link href="/tranfer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DACB Transfers to the Center For Global Christianity and Mission At Boston University School of Theology" /><published>2013-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/tranfer</id><content type="html" xml:base="/tranfer/">The academic year 2011-2012, during which Project Manager Michèle Sigg networked for the DACB while studying at Africa International University (formerly NEGST) in Nairobi, Kenya, represented a year of transition for the Dictionary. During this time, the physical home of the online database was transferred from the Overseas Ministries Study Center (OMSC) to the Center for Global Christianity and Mission (CGCM) directed by Dr. Dana Robert at Boston University School of Theology.

As part of the transfer, Michèle Sigg entered the doctoral program in World Christianity and Christian Mission, starting in the fall of 2012. Since then she has continued in her role as project manager but on a part-time basis, in addition to her studies. Moreover, DACB Project Director Jonathan Bonk retired from his position as Executive Director of OMSC in June of 2013. He will, however, continue in his role as project director of the DACB for the next five years.

The academic year 2013-2014 is another year of planning and transformation for the DACB in the wake of this transition to a new location in a major research university deeply engaged in the study of Christianity in the Global South. During this year, the executive committee of the DACB, composed of Dr. Jonathan Bonk (project director), Dr. Dana Robert (CGCM director), and Michèle Sigg (project manager) will be charting the way forward in dialogue with our partners for the next chapter of the DACB's mission to document the history of African Christianity.</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The academic year 2011-2012, during which Project Manager Michèle Sigg networked for the DACB while studying at Africa International University (formerly NEGST) in Nairobi, Kenya, represented a year of transition for the Dictionary. During this time, the physical home of the online database was transferred from the Overseas Ministries Study Center (OMSC) to the Center for Global Christianity and Mission (CGCM) directed by Dr. Dana Robert at Boston University School of Theology.</summary></entry></feed>